Kevin Meisenbacher

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

kevinmeisenbacher@gmail.com (705)607-9097

https://linkedin.com/in/kevinmeisenbacher

https://github.com/ KevinMeisenbacher

PROFILE

As a lifelong learner who cares deeply about what I do, I took up programming out of passion for improving lives with high-quality software. I love team projects for the opportunity to bring out people's strengths, and I am careful to achieve reliable results for an infinitely unique user base. From 5 years of skill building through Georgian College, BrainStation and personal projects, I am ready to make a meaningful difference as a software engineer!

SKILLS

Front-End: HTML5, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React.js, React Router DOM, JS DOM, Axios, .NET

Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, RESTful APIs, JSON, Knex, User Authentication, OAuth

Databases: MySQL, MS SQL, SQLite, PostreSQL

Testing: JUnit, Jest

Workflow: Git, JIRA

Deployment: AWS, Heroku

Design: Figjam

Desktop: C#, Windows Forms

PROJECTS

Sole Developer | Music Buddy

2024, BRAINSTATION CAPSTONE

- Demonstrated quick learning by making and following a clear Figjam mockup and DB diagram, leading to an attractive and satisfying proof of concept
- Incorporated full-stack skills with a React application that responsively uses back-end queries from a SOLite database, resulting in an intuitive and easy site

Software Engineer | BrainStation Industry Project

2024, BRAINSTATION HACKATHON

- Incorporated back-end skills with an express server that efficiently pulls data from csv files, simplifying work on the front end
- Guided the group to keep in touch and focused on their strengths, resulting in a scalable application that concisely displays accurate data

Sole Developer | Dark Souls Mod Manager

2023, PERSONAL PROJECTS

Showcased problem-solving skills with an intuitive WinForms application that streamlines addition of custom content in Souls games, enhancing convenience for over 2000 users

EDUCATION

BrainStation | **Diploma**, **Software Engineering**

NOV 2023 - JUL 2024, REMOTE

Georgian College | Diploma, Computer Programmer

SEP 2019 - MAY 2021, REMOTE

Dean's List in all semesters

EXPERIENCE

Indie Game Developer | eCo-op

MAY - AUG 2020, REMOTE

Showcased creativity with a niche fighting game where the player's moves generate the soundtrack, garnering interest to people of all types

Golf Equipment Operator | Living Water Resorts

APR 2023 - PRESENT, COLLINGWOOD, ON

Demonstrated high attention to detail by maintaining course features above typical standards, improving golfer experience

Houseperson | Living Water Resorts

APR 2016 - PRESENT, COLLINGWOOD, ON

• Ensured high customer satisfaction by promptly addressing requests and troubleshooting accommodation issues, leading to consistently positive guest reviews